<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: lassie | Halcyon Lane Farm]]></title>
  <link href="http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/categories/lassie/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://collies.halcyonlane.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-11T21:49:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://collies.halcyonlane.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Halcyon Lane]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[mindy@halcyonlane.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Puppies Have Arrived!]]></title>
    <link href="http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/09/09/puppies-have-arrived/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-09T20:29:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/09/09/puppies-have-arrived</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/lassie-circle.png" title="Amish Lassie" alt="Amish Lassie" />
<img src="/images/puppies-1-circle.png" title="Puppies" alt="Puppies" />
<img src="/images/jack-circle.png" title="Captain Jack" alt="Captain Jack" /></p>

<p>Announcing, born to Heritage Captain Jack and Halcyon Amish Lassie,
 on Sunday September 7th, lots of puppies. They were born all through the
night Sunday and into Monday morning, ending up with 9 puppies overall.</p>

<p>There are 6 females and 3 males, all with gorgeous sausage-like bodies.
They look so healthy and chubby! Our children will be holding these puppies
a lot. Lassie does not seem to mind us being around and holding some
puppies now and then, but when she is outside for a break,
 we all pounce and scoop them up for holding time.</p>

<p>Here is a picture (more to follow) with Lassie and the pups:</p>

<p><img src="/images/lassie-with-puppies-1.jpg" width="600" title="&lsquo;Lassie With Pups&rsquo; &lsquo;Lassie with pups&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>As soon as we decide on names we will send in our litter registration to the
<a href="http://www.scotchcollie.org/club/" title="Old-Time Scotch Collie Association">Old-Time Scotch Collie Association</a>.</p>

<p><a href="mailto:mindy@halcyonlane.com">Send us an email</a>
  if you are interested in one of these pups!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Puppies on the way!]]></title>
    <link href="http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/08/19/puppies-on-the-way/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-19T20:54:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/08/19/puppies-on-the-way</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/lassie-circle.png" title="Amish Lassie" alt="Amish Lassie" />
<img src="/images/jack-circle.png" title="Captain Jack" alt="Captain Jack" /></p>

<p>We took Lassie to the vet two weeks ago and she was diagnosed with puppies!
When Lassie was on the Amish farm, she usually had big litters of 8 to 12 pups.
We&rsquo;ll see if that holds true, and if so, we could be in for a lot of fun around our place.
She is due in early September.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve been really excited to see how the combination of Jack and Lassie will turn out.
Lassie introduces an entirely new blood line to the <a href="http://www.scotchcollie.org/club/," title="Old Time Scotch Collie Association">OTSCA</a> registry, and she is a really special dog. Jack brings a great pedigree to the mix, so hopefully
there will be some fantastic puppies to share with the Scotch Collie community soon.</p>

<p>To be placed on our puppy waiting list,
<a href="mailto:mindy@halcyonlane.com">send us an email</a>
with the subject line &ldquo;Gotta have one!&rdquo; and tell us a little about yourself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking care of the farm]]></title>
    <link href="http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/07/14/taking-care-of-the-farm/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-14T21:38:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/07/14/taking-care-of-the-farm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/lassie-circle.png" title="Amish Lassie" alt="Amish Lassie" />
<img src="/images/jack-circle.png" title="Captain Jack" alt="Captain Jack" /></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve been training Jack to keep the goslings out of the back yard.
He is very enthusiastic about helping.
I think Jack&rsquo;s highest motivator is praise from us.
When he does a good job he gives his collie smile and soaks in his reward.</p>

<p>When the goslings were still quite small yet, we were putting them in their
ranging pen. I noticed Lassie, who had been lying nearby,
get up and move a couple of feet over, then lie down. Then she did it again. I couldn&rsquo;t figure out what she was doing until I realized that the family cat was coming close, and Lassie was deliberately placing herself in-between the cat and the goslings!</p>

<p>And not too much later, two goslings didn&rsquo;t come home with the rest and I couldn&rsquo;t find them anywhere.
I assumed they were at the creek still and was not going to worry about it. My mother-in-law told me to ask Jack where they were, but I didn&rsquo;t think he would understand.
So, she took it upon herself to ask Jack where they were and followed him right to the empty silo where the goslings had trapped themselves!
It was really neat to see Jack do a classic collie rescue!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lassie Learns To Play]]></title>
    <link href="http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/06/04/lassie-learns-to-play/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-04T21:02:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/06/04/lassie-learns-to-play</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/lassie-circle.png" title="Amish Lassie" alt="Amish Lassie" /></p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know if Lassie learned how to play with her previous owners. Since she came here, she has seemed puzzled every time we play with Jack. Often she&rsquo;d try to chase him, as if wondering if we want him caught. She seemed jealous, wanting our attention.</p>

<p>Well, this week she turned over a new leaf. Jack brought me a big stick and I threw it for him. After a couple throws, while he was retrieving one, Lassie came up to me with a tiny stick in her mouth! I threw it nearby, and she retrieved it for me! I convinced her to give it to me, and then threw it farther this time. She didn&rsquo;t even try to get it. As long as I threw it close, she&rsquo;d get it. It was as if she knew that Jack would beat her to the distance sticks every time, so established the rules she wanted.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA['Yotes!]]></title>
    <link href="http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/04/29/yotes/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-29T20:54:33-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://collies.halcyonlane.com/blog/2014/04/29/yotes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/lassie-circle.png" title="Amish Lassie" alt="Amish Lassie" />
<img src="/images/jack-circle.png" title="Captain Jack" alt="Captain Jack" /></p>

<p>A couple of mornings ago, I thought I heard the kids calling us
when we were out in the barn doing chores. I ran outside to see what
was going on but the house was quietly sitting there without any sign of
the children.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Jack and Lassie came running, too. They were not fooled by the sound and I soon realized
I was hearing some coyotes yipping across the road at the neighbors field.
Jack went running and barking with Lassie close behind trying with all her
might to keep up with him, with only her three paws.
I was worried they would cross their boundary in all the excitement!</p>

<p>Nope! They ran up on the front porch where there was a commanding view and barked until the coyotes
quieted down. Good job, watch dogs!</p>

<p>We were hoping for puppies this Spring, but it looks like we&rsquo;ll have to wait until next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
